Deleon X. Francis

1011 Pine Street | Apopka, FL 32703

Phone: (407) 437-1137|Email: xavier.xf7@gmail.coml

OBJECTIVE: Seeking employment as an A&P mechanic.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

FAA Airframe and Power Plant Licensed Technician offering four years of experience in aviation maintenance. Dedicated, experienced, and self-motivated professional seeking to learn and utilize my knowledge within the aviation industry. Experienced in Boeing, Airbus, and McDonnell Douglass commercial aircraft family; AH-64D helicopter, Cessna 210, and Beechcraft. Experiences include:

Pneumatics

Hydraulics

Diagnostics

Logistics

• Sheet metal repair & inspection

Hydraulics System Repair Preventative Maintenance Aircraft Disassembly

EXPERIENCE

AIRCRAFT MECHANIC, F&E AIRCAFT MAINTENANCE, Nov-2017 – Present

- Perform A checks on Boeing 757 and 767 aircraft.
- Flight entertainment system maintenance. Airbus A320, 321 and Boeing 737-800.

AH-64D HELICOPER REPAIRER, U.S. ARMY, Jan 2015- July 2016

- Executed aircraft transportation and collaborated with our team to increase aircraft operation readiness.
- Removed and installed aircraft subsystem assemblies such as engines, rotors, gearboxes, transmissions and mechanical flight controls.
- Serviced and lubricated Aircraft Subsystems.
- Prepared aircraft for inspections and maintenance checks.
- Performed scheduled inspections and assisted in performing special Inspections.
- Performed limited maintenance operational checks and assists in diagnosing and troubleshooting Aircraft subsystems using special tools and equipment as required.
- Used and performed operator maintenance on tools, special tools and aircraft ground support equipment.

AIRCRAFT MECHANIC, AVOCET AVIATION, August 2013 – July 2014

- Performed aircraft disassembly of flight controls, instrument, hydraulics and other components on:
 - Boeing's B727, B737, B757, B767, B777
- McDonnell Douglas 80
- Airbus A300, A310, A320, A340-300

EDUCATION

Aviation Institute of Maintenance, Casselberry, FL

Oakwood University, 48 Semester Units in Mechanical Engineering, Huntsville, AL